<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>[Rep] Enemy Bullet Trails</name>
    <directory>bullettrails</directory>
    <id>2949656747</id>
    <description>This mod increases projectile/bullet visibility by giving them a pretty trail. It's extremely customizable through the &quot;Dead Sea Scrolls&quot; menu in game. Access it by pressing [C]!

Note for non-REPENTOGON users: For the option that changes the color to be the color of the bullet (which is now the default), it won't work 100% of the time due to technical limitations. In these cases, it'll default to red. I've only found this to be noticeable on Mega Satan. With REPENOTOGON, this issue should not exist.

/////

Modders, this mod has an api!

[code]
--- Assign a custom trail color to a projectile sender.
---@param entity integer @EntityType
---@param variant integer
---@param color Color | function @A Color object or a function that returns a Color object. The function is provided the entity. Don't use Color.Default, it's mutable and may cause issues.
function BulletTrails:AddEntityTrailColor(entity, variant, color)
[/code]

/////

[code]
--- Blacklist the entity from having any projectile trails.
--- If no variant is provided, all variants of the entity will be blacklisted. (Overwriting any previous variant blacklist)
--- If no subType is provided, all subtypes of the variant of the entity will be blacklisted. (Overwriting any previous subtype blacklist)
---@param bool boolean @Enable/disable
---@param entity integer @EntityType
---@param variant integer?
---@param subType integer?
function BulletTrails:BlacklistEntity(bool, entity, variant, subType)
[/code]

/////

[code]
--- Get a Color object using RGB values.
---@param red number
---@param green number
---@param blue number
function BulletTrails:RGBToColor(red, green, blue)
[/code]

/////

Additionally, you can check if a trail is a trail from the mod by seeing if this is true:
[code]trail:GetData().B_BulletTrail[/code]

You can access the blacklist with:
[code]BulletTrails.EntityTrailBlacklist[/code]

You can access the entity projectile trail color table with:
[code]BulletTrails.TypeToColors[/code]

[b]Make sure you never use Color.Default as one of the colors! This is a mutable color and will have its transparency altered![/b]

--

Please leave feedback in the comments. Bug reports are expected to be detailed, with any errors (red text appearing in the developer console) included.
Thanks to Luni on Discord for the idea to make this mod.</description>
    <version>1.10</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
    <tag id="Graphics"/>
</metadata>
